outrigger.com 2018-10-09

# Privacy Policy - Outrigger Hotels and Resorts

Version 2. Effective May 25, 2018.

Outrigger Hotels Hawaii and our affiliates ("Outrigger", "we" or "us") value your business and respect your right to privacy. The information you provide to us is collected with the intent of serving you better.

Information we ask you to provide

If you make a reservation through our website, through our reservations center, or check in as a guest at one of our properties, we ask for your title, name, address, email address, phone and fax numbers, credit card number and expiration date, and the name(s) of other registered guests in your party. This allows us to secure your reservation and notify you of the status of the reservation.

  * When you participate in a contest or promotion, we may ask for your name, address, phone number and email address to allow us to notify winners.
  * If you log into our website we ask for your account login and password.
  * If you're a travel agent participating in our Outrigger Expert Agent program, we ask for your name, address, email address, phone and fax numbers, travel agency name, consortia affiliation, industry accreditation, and ARC/IATA/CLIA number.
  * If you are participating in our Outrigger Business Connection program, we ask for your company name, address, email address, phone and fax numbers, type of business, and contact information for your company’s designated program administrator(s). 
  * If you are participating in our DISCOVERY Loyalty program, we ask for your title, name, address, email address, and birth date.
  * If you are a guest and log on for Wi-Fi access, we may ask for your name and email address.
  * If you subscribe to receive information from Outrigger via email sign up on our websites, we may ask for your name, address, email address, language preference, birthdate, gender, email frequency, and travel preferences and interests.

You may access, review, correct or delete the personal information you give us by sending us an email or writing us at webmaster@outrigger.com.

How we use the information you provide at our request

Information you provide at our request is used to contact you to confirm a reservation, confirm receipt of a contest entry, or contact you in the event there are questions about any information you submit to us.

We may occasionally notify you of new developments at Outrigger, including new resort openings, new guest services, and seasonal specials. If you do not want to receive any unsolicited announcements from Outrigger, we ask that you indicate this preference when you respond to our request for personal information or please [click to send us an email](mailto:webmaster@outrigger.com). Even if you have given us permission to send emails, you may revoke that permission at any time by following the “unsubscribe” information at the bottom of the email.

Outrigger provides aggregated site statistics to interested parties which do not contain any of the information you provide at our request.

Information we automatically collect and how we use that information

Like many other websites we automatically collect and analyze other information including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; computer and connection information such as browser type, version, and time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system, and platform; the full Uniform Resource Locator (URL) clickstream to, through, and from our website, including date and time. We also collect certain technical information from your computer each time you request a page during a visit to our web sites. We collect this information to enhance the quality of your experience during your visit to our site and will not sell or rent this information to any third parties, except that we may share just your IP address (i.e. with no other identifying information) with advertising partners so that they can display an Outrigger advertisement when you visit the websites of those partners.

Our website may use "Cookies" or "Other Technologies" (such as "pixel tags," "web beacons," "clear GIFs" or similar technologies) to help us and third parties obtain information about your visits to the Site, deliver online and mobile ads and content for us and others specific to your interests, process your reservations or requests, and/or to analyze your visiting patterns.

When you visit our web sites, you will be assigned a persistent "cookie" (a small text file) to be stored on your computer's hard drive. The purpose of the cookie is to identify you when you visit our site so we can enhance and customize your online experience.

You can choose to visit our web sites without cookies, but without these identifying files you will not be able to take advantage of certain desirable features of our site, including providing a more personalized online experience. To visit without cookies, you can configure your web browser to reject all cookies or notify you when a cookie is set. (Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.) You may also delete cookies after they have been downloaded from the Site (in event you do not configure your browser to reject cookies or notify you before a cookie is set). Again, please check the “Help” menu of your browser to learn how to delete cookies using your browser. 

This web site may from time to time offer "web widgets". Some widgets support functions that may require that you to disclose certain personally identifiable information given your choice of participation. This information is collected in many different ways such as: forms, surveys, contests, forums, subscribing or unsubscribing to mailings and correcting or updating personally identifiable information and are only used for the purpose in which they were collected. Some widgets may utilize an optional import contacts feature to help you invite your contacts to download our widget.

This web site may include Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features may be transmitted to the Social Media Company and are governed by that company's privacy policy and terms of use.

We use various web site analytics tools and technologies regarding activities on our website that require storage of web session data. The overall aim of these tools is to learn about how the Site is used, to improve the experience of users of the Site and to proactively identify and correct error conditions. These tools and technologies are also used to assist website visitors who report problems in the use of our website. Stored web session data is never sold or rented to third parties and is purged when these purposes have been fulfilled.

Additional State of California do-not-track disclosures

While you can choose to opt-out of receiving targeted advertising on our website based on your activity across websites, at this time, we do not respond to browser “do-not-track” signals or other similar mechanisms.

Third Party information and services and tools

This site contains or may contain information, services and tools provided by third parties, whether through embedded modules, links or other technologies. Outrigger endeavors to require that any access to or use of personal information gained by any such third parties as a result is governed by applicable law and our applicable policies. Any such access or use may be additionally governed by the privacy policies of such third parties, and you should refer to such privacy policies as well.

Personal Information From Children

We do not knowingly collect personal information from individuals under 18 years of age. As a parent or legal guardian, please do not to allow your children to submit personal information without your permission.

How is your information protected?

Outrigger does not lease, sell, trade or give any of our customer information to other companies except for sharing just your IP address with one of our advertising partners so that Outrigger advertising displays when you visit those partner’s websites.  If you do not want us to provide any of your information to a third party, we ask that you indicate this preference where personal information is requested.  Or please send us an email at webmaster@outrigger.com.

We use generally accepted standards governing administrative, technical and physical measures to protect your personal information.  For example, credit card information provided through our online reservations forms or merchandise order form is encrypted and measures have been taken to secure our server from any unauthorized access.  Despite these measures, the confidentiality of any communication or material transmitted to or from us via the Site by Internet or email cannot be guaranteed.

We recommend that any communications you send us via this site, including comments, suggestions and questions, not contain information that is private or confidential. Credit card information should only be provided on the online reservations or merchandise order forms that encrypt the number for your protection.  While we take reasonable measures to protect your privacy, Outrigger and companies linked to our site do not guarantee and are under no obligation to protect any private or confidential information you choose to provide in an unsecured or unencrypted manner.

We will not contact you by mobile/text messaging or email to ask for your confidential personal information or credit card details. We will only ask for your confidential personal information or credit card details by telephone when you are booking a reservation or promotional package by telephone. 

You may request access to, review, correction, deletion, restriction, objection to further processing or portability of the personal information you give us, or for information on any rights you have to lodge a complaint with an applicable supervisory authority, by sending us an email at webmaster@outrigger.com or writing us at Outrigger Webmaster, 2375 Kuhio Avenue, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA 96815.

Unless you instruct us to delete your personal information, we may retain such information for the periods specified in our records retention and destruction policies. 

For purposes of compliance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), other data protection laws applicable in Member states of the European Union, and other provisions related to data protection:

Our Controller is:

John Neeley  
2375 Kuhio Avenue  
Honolulu, Hawaii  
USA 96815  
Tel: (808) 921-6600  
gdprcontroller@outrigger.com

Our Data Protection Officer is:

GDPR DPO  
2375 Kuhio Avenue  
Honolulu, HI   
USA 96815  
Tel: (808) 921-6600  
gdprdataprotectionofficer@outrigger.com 

Legal Disclaimer

We reserve the right to disclose the information we collect from you as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect the security and reliability of the Site and to take precautions against liability. We may also disclose the information we collect from you to protect the safety of an individual and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, subpoena, search warrant, court order, or an investigation related to public safety.

Future Changes to this Privacy Policy and Your Agreement to Accept This Privacy Policy by Using our Website

By using our website you agree to this Privacy Policy. We have the right to change this Privacy Policy. By using our website after any changes go into effect, you agree to those changes to this Privacy Policy. Printed at the beginning of this Privacy Policy is the version number of this Privacy Policy and the date that it has or will take effect. We encourage you to periodically reread this Privacy Policy to see if there have been any changes to our policies that might affect you.

Outrigger User Generated Content Terms of Use

You're probably reading this because Outrigger Hotels Hawaii has requested your permission to feature content that you posted. You must be at least eighteen (18) years old to participate in this activity.

We reach out to social media users such as yourself to ask for their permission to feature our favorite content on this and our other social media channels, websites, newsletters, emails and more. Please take this opportunity to review these User Generated Content Terms of Use and our general Privacy Policy.

Thank you for considering our request. By responding with the provided hashtag, or otherwise uploading User Content as defined below, we and you are agreeing to the following:

You will retain ownership of all comments, photos, videos and other digital materials (referred to as " **User Content** ") that you post and permit us to use.

You grant Outrigger Hotels Hawaii and its affiliates (collectively, "Outrigger"), a non-exclusive, worldwide, royalty-free, perpetual right and license to reproduce, edit, reformat, publish, broadcast, distribute and otherwise utilize your User Content in connection with OUTRIGGER's advertising, publicity, promotional and marketing activities including, but not limited to, those directed to the public and existing and prospective customers on this and other social media channels, websites, newsletters, and emails. OUTRIGGER's utilization of your User Content may be viewed by you and others. We may elect to display or utilize your handle, your byline or associated geographic or location information when we utilize your User Content.

The nonexclusive nature of our license to your User Content means that you may continue to use the User Content for your own purposes and let others use your User Content. Other than your name or handle, and other information that you elect to provide to OUTRIGGER, OUTRIGGER will not collect personal information from you. OUTRIGGER will maintain the confidentiality of any personal information that you provide, in accordance with our company's Privacy Policy (at <http://www.outrigger.com/privacy-policy>). The royalty-free nature of our license to your User Content means that we do not owe you any compensation or fees in connection with our use of your User Content or in connection with any revenue or business advantage that we might enjoy as a result of such use. The license provides us with the right to utilize your User Content anywhere in the world. Finally, the perpetual nature of the license means that it does not expire.

You will have the right to request that we cease all further use of your User Content, which you may request by notifying us by sending an e-mail request to [social.media@outrigger.com](mailto:social.media@outrigger.com) and providing the following information: First Name, Last Name, email address, content origin, social platform and user handle and media content description. OUTRIGGER will take commercially reasonable steps to cease further use by OUTRIGGER of specifically identified User Content within five (5) business days thereafter. However, OUTRIGGER may not be able to eliminate uses of your User Content that are in the process of production or distribution, and not all User Content is capable of being completely or permanently removed. We may remove User Content from any use or material for any reason and at any time, without notice. Lastly, OUTRIGGER shall not be responsible for any other parties' use of your User Content, even if such third party use originated with or is derived from our use.

You represent to OUTRIGGER that:

  * You are at least eighteen (18) years old;
  * You are not an employee or immediate family member of an employee of OUTRIGGER;
  * You own all rights to your User Content or, alternatively, you have the right to grant OUTRIGGER the rights and license described above;
  * You have paid and will pay in full any fees or other payments that may be related to the production or use of your User Content;
  * Each individual whose image or likeness is captured in your User Content has granted you the right to use his or her image or likeness for the purposes set forth in these User Generated Content Terms of Use, or you otherwise hold the right to make such use of his or her image or likeness on the basis of your legal relationship with each such individual, including, but not limited to, your status as the individual's parent or legal guardian; and
  * Your User Content does not infringe the intellectual property rights, privacy rights, publicity rights, or other legal rights of any third party, and does not contain any offensive, unlawful or obscene material.

You acknowledge that as part of your provision to OUTRIGGER of your User Content you provided your name and email address to OUTRIGGER and that such provision was and is on and subject to the terms and conditions of these User Generated Content Terms of Use and of OUTRIGGER’S general Privacy Policy

 You acknowledge that OUTRIGGER has reasonably relied on the above representations and that you shall be responsible for and indemnify OUTRIGGER against any claims and liabilities that may result from the inaccuracy of these representations or from the content of your User Content.

These User Generated Content Terms of Use shall for all purposes be governed by and construed in accordance with the law of the State of Hawaii, United States without regard to any conflict of laws provisions, and any dispute relating thereto shall be subject to the nonexclusive jurisdiction of the courts of the State of Hawaii or the federal counts located in the State of Hawaii.

These User Generated Content Terms of Use were most recently updated on March 31, 2018. Please refer back to these User Generated Content Terms of Use in order to review the most current version each time that you grant us permission to use your User Content.

Thank you!
